By now, most of us will have heard of GMOs.
到目前为止，我们大多数人都听说过转基因生物（GMOs）。
In case you haven't, GMO stands for genetically-modified organism.
如果你还不了解，GMO是“genetically-modified organism”的缩写，即转基因生物。
This basically means that an organism has had a foreign genetic sequence introduced into it.
这本质上意味着一种生物被植入了外来基因序列。
In theory, this gives the organism certain advantages – it may become hardier by developing a resistance to disease, or in the case of GM food, may be bigger and require fewer nutrients to develop.
理论上，这会赋予该生物某些优势——它可能通过产生抗病性变得更顽强，而就转基因食品而言，它可能会更大，且生长所需的营养更少。
GM organisms have been used for a while.
转基因生物的应用已有一段时间了。
Scientists in the UK are trialling a GM wheat which allegedly yields 40% more crop in greenhouse conditions.
英国科学家正在试验一种转基因小麦，据称在温室条件下其产量能提高40%。
GM hens, which are able to lay eggs from different poultry breeds, have been used by scientists in Edinburgh to conserve rare birds by storing their stem cells in a seed bank.
爱丁堡的科学家利用转基因母鸡（这种母鸡能产下不同家禽品种的鸡蛋），将稀有鸟类的干细胞储存在种子库中，以保护这些珍稀物种。
And more recently, scientists in China used information from the genome of a plant to increase the production of a key malaria drug, helping to meet the large global demand.
最近，中国科学家利用一种植物的基因组信息，提高了一种关键抗疟药物的产量，助力满足全球的巨大需求。
But now scientists at the University of Edinburgh's Roslin Institute have created GE pigs which are allegedly immune to one of the world's costliest livestock diseases.
但如今，爱丁堡大学罗斯林研究所的科学家们培育出了基因编辑（GE）猪，据称这种猪对全球代价最大的家畜疾病之一具有免疫力。
GE stands for gene editing.
GE是“gene editing”的缩写，即基因编辑。
Unlike GM, gene editing merely alters the DNA of the creature.
与仅对生物的DNA进行修饰的转基因不同。
In this case, a small region of pig DNA was deleted, preventing contraction of the PRRS virus, or Porcine Reproductive and Respiratory Syndrome virus.
在这个案例中，研究人员删除了猪DNA中的一个小片段，使其能够抵抗猪繁殖与呼吸综合征病毒（PRRS病毒）。
The virus causes breathing problems and death, but even after the GE pigs were exposed to it, none have become ill.
这种病毒会导致呼吸问题甚至死亡，但即使基因编辑猪接触到该病毒，也没有出现发病情况。
And the effect is permanent, so the resistance will be passed on through natural breeding.
而且这种效果是永久性的，因此抗病性会通过自然繁殖传递给后代。
Tests so far showed that the animals are not weakened in any other way by the process, claims Research leader Dr Christine Tait-Burkard.
研究负责人克里斯汀·泰特-伯卡德博士表示，迄今为止的测试表明，这一过程没有以任何其他方式影响这些动物的健康。
"The main thing that this edit will do is benefit animal welfare because the animals will not get a devastating disease."
“这种基因编辑的主要作用是改善动物福利，因为这些动物不会再感染这种毁灭性的疾病。”
However, critics have argued that the creature's welfare will actually suffer because of this.
然而，批评者认为，这种做法实际上会损害动物。
Helen Browning of the Soil Association believes this only addresses the symptom of the problem and not the root cause.
土壤协会的海伦·布朗宁认为，这只是治标不治本。
"It is not encouraging companies to change the way they keep their pigs so they don't become diseased in the first place", she says.
“它并没有鼓励企业改变养猪方式，从源头上避免猪患病，”她说。
Regardless, this is an experiment and while the technique appears to work, it is several years away from regulation and implementation.
尽管如此，这仍处于实验阶段。
“On top of that, only if these studies are successful and the public are accepting, would we integrate these gene edits into commercial breeding stocks,"
虽然该技术看似有效，但距离监管批准和实际应用还需要数年时间。
Dr Tait-Burkard told the BBC.
泰特-伯卡德博士告诉英国广播公司：“此外，只有当这些研究取得成功且获得公众认可时，我们才会将这些基因编辑技术应用到商业育种中。”
So it seems we may have a while yet.
因此，看来我们还需要等待一段时间。